Alexandros Trifyllis

2 Personal Information

Date of birth 07/06/1980

🖾 a.trifyllis@gmail.com 🥒 +306942473470 🕲 atrifyllis 🗘 https://github.com/atrifyllis

Summary

I am a full-stack senior developer with more than 12 years of experience.

My areas of expertise and interest are backend development using **Spring/Spring Boot** technologies (or Java EE) and frontend development using Typescript (or Javascript) with AngularJS/**Angular 2+**. I am interested in both the design/architecture phase of a project as well as the development phase. I am also interested in **Devops, Continous delivery** and performance tuning. I consider myself a problem-solver and a solution-oriented developer. I like working in **Agile** teams and co-operating with my colleagues, sharing knowledge and expertise so as **to provide the best possible result for the customers**.

Job-related skills

Backend Frontend / Other • Languages: Java, Kotlin (beginner), Groovy · Languages: Typescript, Javascript (using DSLs mainly), (some C and C# in the • Frameworks: Angular JS/Angular 2+, (jQuery past) in the past), (some Vue.js) • Web Frameworks: **Spring**, Java EE 7 • State management: ngrx (Redux) • Spring Projects: **Spring Boot**, MVC, Data, • Testing: Jasmine, Jest, Karma, Selenium JMS, Security, AOP, Hateoas, Cloud • Other: HTML, CSS/SCCS, Bootstrap, PrimeNG · Java EE JSRs: CDI, EJB, JPA, JMS, JAX-RS, JAX-WS (CXF), JSF Other Tools & Methodologies • ORMs: Hibernate, EclipseLink • Version control systems: Git, SVN • Databases: Oracle, MS SQL Server, MySQL, Collaboration tools: Jira, Confluence, (some DB2 in the past) BitBucket, Github, Gitlab • Database migration: Flyway, Liquibase • IDEs: IntelliJ, (Eclipse, Netbeans in the past) • Application Servers: **Tomcat**, • Continuous Integration: Jenkins, Sonar, Wildfly, (Websphere in the past) Artifactory/Nexus · Build Tools: Maven • Monitoring/Logging: SLF4J (logback or log4j), • Testing: jUnit, Mockito, Arquillian, AssertJ, ELK stack, VisualVm Hamcrest, jMeter, Testcontainers · Methodologies: Agile methods, SCRUM • Infrastructure: **Docker**, Docker compose, · Business Modelling: UML, Activiti BPM Docker swarm (some Kubernetes)

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Trasys Greece, Athens (Greece)

☐ January 2016 to Now (On going)

As a Software Engineer in Trasys I was part of several teams/projects for clients including European Organisations and the private sector. I was involved in design and development of web applications using Java/Spring/Java EE on the backend and Angular/Angular 2+ on the frontend.

Some of the projects I was involved in include:

- Design and development of a REST API and also complete rewrite of the frontend part for a legacy web application for a European Agency. Technologies used were Spring Boot, Angular 7 (Bootstrap, ngrx), Oracle DB. I was mainly responsible for the frontend architecture, but also worked on backend features. I was also responsible for creating Jenkins pipelines using Groovy DSL.
- Design and development of a modular web application used for administration tasks for a DG of the European Commission (Contacts management, User management, etc.). The technologies used were **Spring Boot**, **Angular 4** (PrimeNG, Bootstrap, ngrx, eUI). Oracle DB. I was mainly responsible for the frontend architecture, but also worked on backend features.
- Development of the Cloud Infrastructure project for a European Agency. This agency provides for its clients a private cloud space were they can manage instances of its applications. This cloud infrastructure consists of several microservices and the technologies used were Java EE, **RxJava** and **Apache Kafka**.
- Development of existing web application of banking sector client used for managing sanction lists. Technologies used were **Spring**, **AngularJS**, Oracle DB.
- Development of web application for a European Agency, used by the members state to submit Clinical Trials. I was responsible for developing several features in **Java EE/AngularJS**, for the backend validation solution/ infrastructure and for creating a 'Test Object' infrastructure. I also worked on some features in Activiti.
- Support and development on the Reportnet platform of the European Environment Agency. My role was to coordinate with the rest of the dev team for the support and development activities. I was responsible for designing and implementing a PoC for an Angular 6 dynamic forms library, to be used potentially in several web applications. Technologies used were **Spring/Spring Boot**, **XQuery**, **Angular 5**, **Vue.js**, **Rancher**.

Software Engineer at Interbanking Systems S.A., Athens (Greece)

September 2010 to December 2015

As a Software Engineer in Interbanking Systems, I worked in several in-house and external projects as both Software engineer and technical lead designing and implementing mainly web applications in **Java/Spring** on the backend and **jQuery** on the frontend.

Some of the projects I was involved in include:

- Development and integration with a new Eurozone e-payment system. Interbanking Systems was responsible for implementing a solution that will be used by the Greek Banks to connect to the central e-payment system "hub". The solution is implemented using Java EE 7 (deployed in Wildfly), Web Services using JAX-WS (CXF) and the challenging requirement was the integration with advanced security mechanisms (WS-Security, WS-SecurityPolicy, WS-Addressing etc.). The database used is MS SQL Server.
- Technical management and development of web application (e-Payments) for the General Secretariat for Information Systems (Spring Web Application). Solved critical issues with Weblogic integration. Implemented Taxisnet integration, web services and adapter for connecting to Interbanking Services Online Payment System.
- Developed internal backend services using C.
- Responsible for setting up the continuous delivery infrastructure for the companies application Sector (Jenkins/ Artifactory/Sonar).

Software Engineer at Byte S.A., Athens (Greece)

□ October 2007 to June 2010

As as Software engineer in Byte, I worked in several projects for our clients mostly doing full-stack development using Java/J2EE* in backend and jQuery/Javascript in frontend.

Some of the projects I was involved in include:

- Design, development and support of web application "Life Quotation" for a large insurance company. The application's purpose is the creation of insurance offers about Life, Health and Pension. Development in **J2EE** (single-page application), communication with Web Services of the insurance company. Other technologies: **Servlets**, **JSP**, **jQuery**, **JiBX**, **Websphere**.
- Design, development and support of web application about the monitoring of a warehouse's production process (packaging transporting of mobile phone products). Development in Java EE (Ajax enabled application). MS SQL backend. Other technologies: Servlets, JSP, Javascript, Tomcat.

Software Engineer at Lambrakis press S. A., Athens (Greece)

☐ January 2005 to July 2005

Developed the Customer Management Application for the Archive Department. Technology used was **C**#.

Education and Training

Academic Background

■ Oxford university, United Kingdom

10/2005 - 10/2006

Title: Master of Science in Computer Science

Level: Master Degree

1 School of Engineering, University of Patras, Greece

Ö 09/1998 - 09/2004

Title: Diploma in Computer Engineering and Informatics

Level: University (5-years)

<u>m</u> European School of Brussels, Belgium

1 01/1988 - 07/1998

Title: European Baccalaureate Certificate

Level: Secondary school

***** Certifications/Training

Title	Date	Туре	Institute
Machine Learning	29/10/2018	Certification	Stanford University, Coursera
Oracle Java SE 8 Programmer I	02/06/2017	Certification	Oracle

Languages

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING	
	Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production		
Greek	Native					
English	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1	
French	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1	
German	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1	



Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages